thumb.it 2015-04-07

# Thumb - Privacy Policy

#### THUMB'S PRIVACY STATEMENT

Welcome to Thumb! Ypulse, Inc. (“ **Ypulse** ,” “ **Thumb** ,” “ **Opinionaided** ,” “ **we** ,” “ **us** ,” or “ **our** ”) operates this website ( **thumb.it** ) (the “ **Site** ”) as well as a number of related services, including our mobile applications (collectively, the “ **Services** ”). The focus of our Site and Service is to let You get opinions, give opinions, communicate with other users, and connect with people like you.

Privacy is of great importance to us whether You are a “ **Visitor** ” (which means that you simply browse the Site (defined below)) or a “ **Member** ” of Thumb (which means you have either registered with Thumb or established an account). Visitors and Members are individually referred to as a “ **User** ,” and collectively, as “ **Users** ” Because we gather important information from our Users, we have established this Privacy Statement as a means to communicate our information collection, use and dissemination practices.

So we are clear on the terminology we use, “ **Personal Information** ” means contact information (e.g., your name, address, email address, and/or telephone number) and any other non-public information that is used or intended to be used to personally identify an individual, and any other non-public information that is associated with that information. “ **Anonymous Information** ” means information that is not used or intended to be used to personally identify an individual.

**BY USING OUR SITE OR SERVICES OR SUBMITTING PERSONAL INFORMATION THROUGH OUR SITE OR SERVICES, YOU AGREE TO THE TERMS OF THIS PRIVACY STATEMENT AND YOU EXPRESSLY CONSENT TO THE PROCESSING OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION ACCORDING TO THIS PRIVACY STATEMENT. YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION MAY BE PROCESSED BY US IN THE COUNTRY WHERE IT WAS COLLECTED AS WELL AS OTHER COUNTRIES (INCLUDING THE UNITED STATES) WHERE LAWS REGARDING PROCESSING OF PERSONAL INFORMATION MAY BE LESS STRINGENT THAN THE LAWS IN YOUR COUNTRY.**

**Children.** The Site and Services are not directed to children and children are not eligible to use our Services. Protecting the privacy of children is very important to us. We do not collect Personal Information from people we actually know are under 13 years of age. If we later learn that a user is under 13 years of age, we will take steps to prevent the User from utilizing the Site and the Services.

**Collected Information** In general, the Personal Information we gather enables us to provide the Services to you and helps us learn more about the use of the Site and/or Services. We collect Personal Information that you submit to us voluntarily at registration and in the course of using the Site and/or Services, including the questions and opinions you post on the Site or through the Services. To use the Services you must create an “ **Account** ” by providing your name, email address, gender, age, location, additional preferences, a password, and potentially additional information. You may alternatively connect to the Site or Services through Facebook, in which case we may collect that information (less the password but including a photograph), from Facebook for the purposes of creating your Account on the Site. When you communicate with us by sending us an email, we will collect and store any information that is contained in your communications with us.

When you register, we will create a profile for you that includes your first name and first letter of your last name and any other information you want to provide, including, but not limited to, your gender, location, relationship status, your bio and a profile picture. We may collect information about your location in a variety of ways, including through Facebook and through functionality enabled in native mobile applications. If you registered through Facebook, we may use the information we collected about you from Facebook to pre-populate your Profile. You can choose not to provide us with certain information, but the Services have more relevancy when you provide this information, and you may be able to make more meaningful connections.

We will refer to all of the information contained in your Profile as your “ **Profile Information** ”. As your Profile Information is intended by you to be published on the Site, your Profile Information will not be considered Personal Information under this Agreement, even if it contains Personal Information and we may use and disclose the Profile Information on the Site without restriction.

We will refer to the questions asked through the Site and Services as "Questions" and responses to Questions as "Responses".

If you access the Services from your mobile device, we will collect your unique device identifier, the application version you are using, and your event activity.

If you choose to use our “Refer to a Friend” feature, we will ask for your friends email address. We will send your friend a one time email inviting them to visit the site. We do not store this information or use it for any other purpose other than to fulfill send the email at your request.

If you make a purchase through the Services, we collect information about the purchase including the specific goods or services you have purchased, the date you made the purchase and the fees paid. We let you know, however, that we do NOT have access to your billing information, such as your credit card number and credit card expiration date, which is collected directly by the payment processor and governed by the payment processor’s privacy policy and not ours (e.g., the privacy policy of the Apple Store if you purchase the Services on your iPhone).

_Anonymous Information_

As you use the Site or Services, certain Anonymous Information may be passively collected and stored, such as your Internet protocol address, domain names, browser type, and access times. We may also use Cookies (as defined below) or web bugs and navigational data like Uniform Resource Locators (URLs) to gather information regarding the date and time of your visit and the solutions and information for which You searched and viewed, or on which advertisements displayed on the Site You have viewed and/or clicked. “Cookies” are small pieces of information that a website sends to your browser while you are viewing a website. We may use both session Cookies (which expire once you close your web browser) and persistent Cookies (which stay on your browser until you delete them) to improve your experience on the Site (e.g., by keeping you logged in). Many consider the use of cookies to be industry standard. Persistent Cookies can be removed by following your Internet browser help file directions. If you choose to disable Cookies, you may experience session errors and may need to log-in again for each page you visit on the Site.

**Disclosure – Usage of Third Party Cookies** We may use a third party tracking service to track and analyze Anonymous Information from Users of our Site. Such third parties may use Cookies to help track User behavior. Additionally, we may also enable advertisers and ad servers to promote third-party products and/or services by placing advertisements on the Site. These advertisers and ad servers may use Cookies in order to monitor information related to served advertisements. Clicking on such advertisements will direct You to the website of a third-party and the advertiser. This Privacy Statement does not cover the privacy practices of any advertisers or ad servers.

**Our Relationship with Social Networking Site** We have created and may offer You interfaces that allow You to connect with social networking websites such as Facebook (“ **SN Site** ”) through our Site. We will work with the SN Site’s application protocol interface (better known as their developer API) in a way that allows You to authorize us to access Your account on that SN Site on Your behalf. In order to provide this authorization, You will not provide us with Your user name or password to the SN Site, but You will need to log-in to that SN Site directly through our Site. Once authorized by You, the SN Site will provide us a token that allows the SN Site to recognize us when we ask, on Your behalf, for access to Your account information or to post information. You will be able to revoke our access to any SN Site at any time by amending the appropriate settings from within Your account settings on the applicable SN Site, though such revocation may limit the Services we are able to provide You.

**USE OF INFORMATION**

Personal Information. We will use your Personal Information to:

  * Administer your Account;
  * Provide you and other Members with Services and customer support;
  * Target content to You or on Your behalf – for example, a User can restrict the distribution of a question to Users that fall within a particular age group
  * Market our products and services (and those of third parties) to You that we believe may be of interest to You, including through the serving of personalized advertisements, though we will not disclose Your Personal Information in doing so. For example, we allow advertisers to choose the characteristics of users who will see their advertisements and we may use any of attributes we have collected (including information You do not make available on the Site) to select the appropriate audience for those advertisements. For example, if you tend to ask questions about automobiles, we might use that interest to show You ads for automobiles. In that case, we do not tell any automobile dealer or manufacturer who You but the dealer or manufacturer may learn that You possess certain characteristics based on the fact that You received the advertisement;
  * Respond to your requests, resolve disputes and/or troubleshoot problems;
  * Verify your compliance with your obligations in our Terms of Use or other Thumb policies;
  * Improve the quality of the Site and the Services; and
  * Communicate with you about the Site and the Services.

We may also use your Personal Information to create Anonymous Information records by excluding information that makes the information personally identifiable to you.

We may send you communications via email about the Site and Services. You can opt out of receiving certain communications from the Site by clicking the “Unsubscribe” link at the bottom of each email. Please note that even if you unsubscribe or opt-out, we may still send you Site and Service related communications (e.g., emails related to your Account).

Profile Information, Questions and Responses

To be clear, profile Information, Questions and Responses that are associated with your name, email or other identifying information is considered Personal Information and we use such Profile Information, Questions and Responses in all of the ways we use Personal Information.

Anonymous Information

We may, through our use of Cookies and web bugs, keep you logged into our Site, track your session history, collect your click-stream data, and personalize your experience on the Site. We may use your Anonymous Information to analyze usage patterns so that we may enhance the Site or Services, improve our internal operations and the content of our software, notify visitors about updates to our Site or Services, and improve the efficacy of our content and advertisements that appear on the Site. We may also use your Anonymous Information (including Cookies) to market our products and services to you, whether on our Site or on third party websites.

**DISCLOSURE OF INFORMATION**

Personal Information

We may disclose certain Personal Information:

  * To third party vendors who act on our behalf and help us provide the Services or the Site;
  * To third parties, including other Members and our promotional partners, to whom you ask us to send Personal Information;
  * To commercial Thumb members, including market researchers, with whom you have directly interacted through the Services or the Site;
  * To a parent company, any subsidiaries, joint ventures, or other companies under a common control (collectively, “Affiliates”), in the event we have such Affiliates in the future, in which case we will require our Affiliates to honor this Privacy Policy;
  * To a company that merges with us, acquires us, or purchases our assets, in which case such company may continue to process your Personal Information as set forth in this Privacy Policy; or
  * If we believe in good faith that such disclosure is necessary to (a) resolve disputes, investigate problems, or enforce our Terms of Use; (b) comply with relevant laws or to respond to requests from law enforcement or other government officials relating to investigations or alleged illegal activity, in which case we can (and you authorize us to) disclose Personal Information without subpoenas or warrants served on us; or (c) protect and defend our rights or property or the rights and property of you or third parties.

We provide Members who seek opinions through the Services with the opportunity to communicate with responding Members. All such communication is directly through the Services, and we have access to this information as a result. Through this communication, another Member may request additional information from you. Such sharing of information is entirely your choice. Please be judicious about the information you share through the Site and Services.

Profile Information

We may share your Profile Information publicly on the Site and through our Services, including to Members whose questions you thumbed on through the Service and to your friends on the Site. Additionally, if you ask a question and another Member provides a comment in addition to a thumbs up or thumbs down, we will make your Profile Information available to that Member.

Questions

Each time you ask a Question, you have an opportunity to define the set of people to whom the Question is sent (e.g., Thumb public, Thumb friends, your phone’s contact list or some other defined set). We disclose the Question you asked in association with your name as it appears in your Profile to the individuals you authorize.

Responses

Each time you provide a Response to a Question asked by another Member, we provide your Response to that Member along with your name as it appears in your Profile.

Please remember that this is a community-oriented Site. You are welcome to share as much Profile Information as you think is necessary and appropriate. But please be aware than any Profile Information will be made available on your Profile, which may be available to other Members and/or Visitors.

Anonymous Information

We may disclose Anonymous Information without restriction.

**FEEDBACK** If You provide feedback to us, we may use and disclose such feedback for any purpose, provided we do not associate such feedback with Your Personal Information. We will collect any information contained in such feedback and will treat the Personal Information in it in accordance with this Privacy Statement.

**Accessing And Controlling Your Information.** You can review and/or change any of your Personal Information or Profile Information by logging into the Site and accessing your Account. You authorize us to use and disclose any new or modified information that you provide in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Please remember, however, if we have already disclosed some of your Personal Information or Profile Information to third parties, we cannot access that Personal Information or Profile Information any longer and cannot force the deletion or modification of any such information by the parties to whom we have made those disclosures.

Upon your request, we will close your Account. We may continue to use your Profile Information in accordance with this Privacy Policy even after we have closed your account. In addition, we may retain your Personal Information and Profile Information to comply with laws, prevent fraud, resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems, assist with any investigations, enforce our Terms of Use, and take other actions otherwise permitted by law.

**Information Disclosed to Third Parties** This Privacy Policy addresses only our use and disclosure of information we collect from and/or about you. If you disclose information to others, including to other Members or our promotional partners, the use and disclosure restrictions contained in this Privacy Policy will not apply to any third party. We do not control the privacy policies of third parties, and you are subject to the privacy policies of those third parties where applicable.

The Site or Services may contain links to other websites that are not owned or controlled by us. We have no control over, do not review and are not responsible for the privacy policies of or content displayed on such other websites. When you click on such a link, you will leave our Site or Services and go to another site. During this process, another entity may collect Personal Information or Anonymous Information from you.

**Changes to this Privacy Policy.** This Privacy Policy is subject to revision from time to time on a going-forward basis. We will post any revised version of the Privacy Policy on this page. If we make any material changes to it, we will also send you notice thereof to the last email address you have provided to us. Continued use of our Services following notice of such changes will indicate your acknowledgement of such changes and agreement to be bound by the terms and conditions of such changes.

**Contact Us.** If you have questions or concerns about our Privacy Policy, please contact us by sending an email to: [help@thumb.it](mailto:help@thumb.it "Email: help@thumb.it").

This Policy was last revised: July 11, 2013.
